カイジら４５組が
全てを賭けて挑んだ大勝負
Kaiji and the 45s risk it all on this bet!
The foreman Ohtsuki uses the 4-5-6 dice for his third roll!
班長大槻　シゴロ賽を
選択しての３投目
その時…
And then!
ああっ！
何をする！
What the hell are you doing!?
こら！まだ回ってんじゃねえか！
They're still rolling!
Karmic Punishment
カイジさん
カイジさん！
Kaiji!
こら こいつ！返せ こら！
Hey! You!
Give those back!
いくらいい目が出そうだからって
なんて無法だ！
You're just breaking the rules because you could tell I rolled well!
だ… 黙れ！
うおっ！
Shut up!
Gotta fight fire with fire!
無法には無法だ！
えっ？
みんな　聞け！こいつらは…
まずい！
Listen, everyone!
Oh crap! They—
They're...
バ… バカ野郎！
クソ！
Idiot!
Dammit!
しゃべらせるな！
Don't say it!
ああ！アタタタ！
Owww!
聞け　こいつらは
イカサマをした！
They're cheating!
な… 何を言うか！
What!?
ち 違う！違う 違う 違う！
No! No no no!
違わない ここに証拠を握り込んだ
イカサマサイコロ！
Yes! I have the proof in my hand!
These are loaded dice!
ふざけるな！
Bullshit!
Give those back, you brat!
返せ！このガキ！
You keep making shit up!
次から次へと
根も葉もないことを…
許さん　許さんぞ！
I won't let you get away with it!
よせ 大槻
えっ？あっ…
Back of, Ohtsuki.
俺たちが改めよう
We'll handle this.
Odagiri, foreman of team C, speaks!
申し出たのはＣ班の班長 小田切
あっいや… ここはわしらが
Seriously, we're fine...
またまた　それじゃ
意味がないだろ
It's pointless for you to do it.
見れくれ　これが奴らの
常勝の秘密だ
Look! This is why they win so often!
あっ… ま 待て
Wait!
ああ！ま 待ってくれ！それは…
Hold it! That's—!
His false luck is revealed!
さらされる偽りの強運
ダメ！
No!
そのからくりが白日の下
The trick is thrust into the light of day!
おっ… 何だ？こりゃ
What are these!?
何だ？どうした？おい
何だよ？
These dice only have sides with fours, fives, and sixes!
このサイコロ
目が４と５と６だけじゃねえか
あいつら こんなものを？
That's what he's been using!?
ひでえ…
What a dick!
How long have you been using these?
いつから使ってたんだ？これ
も… もちろん さっきが初めてだ
That was the first time, of course!
I didn't even plan on using them today!
あっいや… 今日だって
使うつもりはなかったんだ
何言ってやがる！
実際 使ってるじゃねえか！
What the fuck are you talking about!?
You went and used 'em!
そうだそうだ　とぼけんな！
Yeah! Don't play dumb!
いやいやいや　これは
後で余興でやろうと思って
No, really! I was gonna show 'em off later, but I accidentally rolled with the wrong set!
それが交ざってしまって
ふざけんな！
誰がそんな話 信じる！
Bullshit! No one's gonna buy that!
いや その証拠に２投目までは
このサイコロを使わなかっただろ
But I didn't use them for my first two rolls!
このサイコロはな
ションベンさえしなければ
See, these dice are sure to roll something unless you roll a pisser!
必ず目が出る
最低でも４の目がな
They can't roll worse than a 4!
つまり さっきの１ ２投目は
So obviously I was using normal dice for my first two rolls!
普通のサイコロを
使ってたってことだ
What if I had rolled something crappy my first time? See, I can't be cheating!
そんなことをして
もし１投目に弱い目が出たら
イカサマサイコロを
持ってる意味なんか
ないじゃないか な？
使うなら１投目だ
うっ…
If I was gonna use them, I'd have started with them.
See, that proves I wasn't using loaded dice!
これこそ わしがｲｶｻﾏｻｲｺﾛを
使ってないという証拠だろ
Wrong.
違うな
は？
さっきの勝負は特別だったのさ
That last round was special.
Sure, if you were planning to win with the 4-5-6 dice, you'd have used them first.
確かにシゴロ賽で
勝とうと思ったら
使うのは１投目
Up until now, you always have when push came to shove.
今までのあんたは
この基本どおり
大勝負では こいつを使ってきた
Now you're just making shit up!
言いがかりだ
いいや
Nope.
俺も この三好メモを見るまでは
気づかなかったんだが
I never realized until I read Miyoshi's notes,
あんた多すぎた
１投目に強い目が出る割合が
but you win on the first roll way too often.
Way too often for it to be by chance.
偶然の域をはるかに超えている
I'm a moron for not seeing it, but it's just part of what makes the 4-5-6 dice so terrible.
気づかなかった俺も間抜けだが
そいつは このシゴロ賽の持つ
タチの悪さみたいなもんでよ
シゴロ賽は必ずしも
シゴロが出るわけではない
The 4-5-6 dice do not always roll a 4-5-6!
４の目 ５の目もある
They can roll a 4 or a 5 too!
その場合 相手が勝つこともある
Then the other player can win! So in a way, they're the perfect cheat!
これがある意味 絶妙の煙幕となり
このシゴロ賽の存在を
隠したのである
The existence of the 4-5-6 dice was concealed!
事実 俺もしょっぱなの勝負じゃ
Even I won against their 4 twice in a row.
この賽で出た４の目に対して
５の目で２連勝
大喜びしたってわけだ
I enjoyed it plenty then.
だが記録ってのは
冷静で客観的なもんだ
But the records speak for themselves.
このメモで あんたのイカサマに
気づいた俺は
When I realized you were cheating by reading these notes, I planned a showdown.
こいつらと大勝負を仕掛けた
最初に２万という大金を張って
そっちの出方を見たが
First, I'd bet 20 thou, and see what you did.
１番手の石和が能天気に
イカサマサイコロを使ってきた
Isawa rolled first, and went straight for the loaded dice.
俺は内心 ほくそえんで
あんたの親番を待ち
I grinned on the inside, waiting for your turn to deal.
みんなを呼んで大勝負に出た
Then I called everyone in and bet the farm.
But the size of the bet told you something was up.
だが金額のデカさが
あんたの猜疑心を
揺り起こしちまった
You realized we were on to you.
イカサマが
バレてるんじゃないかってな
だからあんた この土壇場で
That's why you couldn't decide whether to use your loaded dice or not.
シゴロ賽を使うことを
思いとどまった
How could you tell?
どうして思いとどまったって
分かったんだ？
普通 チンチロってのは
Normally in chinchiro, once you roll, everyone's focused on the bowl.
サイコロを
どんぶりに投げ入れたら
誰だって どんぶりの中に
集中するはずだ
But during your first roll...
だが１投目 あんた俺の目を見た
You were looking straight into my eyes.
あっ！
俺がイカサマに気づいてるか
Trying to see if I knew you were cheating.
確かめにきたんだ
フッ 助かったぜ
I'm lucky. If you hadn't been looking at me like that,
あの目がなきゃ
俺は普通のサイコロを
I'd have thought they were the loaded dice and made a grab.
イカサマサイコロと思い込んで
とんだ お手つきをしてたところだ
The second roll was the same, so I stayed still.
そして２投目も同じ
これじゃ手も足も出ない
But with that much on the line, you couldn't just leave it up to luck.
だが ほぼ勝ちを拾えるシゴロ賽
大金を前にして できることなら
運否天賦に任せず
こいつを使って勝ちたい
That was your fatal mistake.
そのスケベ心が命取りになった
あんたは１ ２投目の俺や
三好たちの反応を見て
You watched me and Miyoshi during your first two rolls and decided we weren't on to you.
イカサマに気づかれてないと
判断した
シゴロ賽を使わないことを
No one seemed surprised that you weren't using the 4-5-6 dice.
誰も不思議がって
いなかったからな
当然だ　こいつらには
イカサマの仕組みに関しては
Of course not. I said nothing to them about your trick.
何も話してなかったんだからな
えっ？
それも俺の戦略
That was part of my plan too.
And you walked right into it.
あんたは まんまと乗ってきた
On the third roll, you didn't look at me.
３投目 もう俺に目もくれなかった
あんたは故意に
このサイコロを使ったんだよ
You were using these dice to win!
勝つためにな
No way, Kaiji!
違う　違うんだよ カイジ君
こ… こいつ気づいてやがった
Damn it, he noticed!
本当に故意じゃなかったんだよ
It wasn't on purpose at all!
Everything! He noticed everything!
何もかも
事故なんだ
まだすっとぼけんのかよ！
It was accidental!
Don't keep giving us that!
そうだ
バカ野郎！
Yeah!
You son of a bitch!
Really! Believe me!
信じてくれ　このとおりだ
ふざけんな！
お前はイカサマをしたんだよ！
Bullshit!
You're a dirty cheater!
そうだ そうだ！
金返せ！
Yeah!
Give the money back!
Crap! How can I turn this around!?
ま… マズい　どうすれば
わしの立場は逆転できる？
このままイカサマを認めれば
どんな目に遭うか
What's gonna happen to me if I admit I was cheating?
This is the worst moment of my life!
我が生涯 最大の苦境！
It's all that kid's fault!
元はといえば あのガキのせい
But he's not just some kid!
だが あいつは単なるガキじゃない
今にして思えば
あの露骨なまでの反抗も
Thinking of it, even that blatant disrespect was just to make me angry!
わしの敵がい心をあおるための
計算ずくの行動
まんまと踊らされていた…
He took me in completely!
Cheater!
イカサマ野郎！
金返せ！
Pay us back!
クズが！
単に金が欲しいだけなら
You suck!
If this was just about about money, I might not have used them!
わしもシゴロ賽を
使わなかったかもしれん
だが あのガキに対する憎悪が
But my anger pushed me into it!
わしの背中を押した
最後の最後に使ってしまった
In the end, I used them!
なんたる不覚！
不覚！不覚！不覚！
What a mistake!
An error! A misjudgment!
A failure!
しかしカイジ君
あんた大したもんだ
Not bad, Kaiji.
ほんとだよな
まだサイコロが回ってる時に
Yeah. I'm amazed you went for the bowl while the dice were still rolling.
どんぶりに手を入れるから
ああ 最初は
何事かと思ったけどな
I couldn't figure out what you were up to.
ああ！
ひらめく！大槻の脳裏に突破口
A flash of inspiration!
Ohtsuki's mind races!
打ち立てる 己の議
An insight comes to him, as well!
His logic! His argument! His justice!
正論　正しさ　身勝手な正義
死ね！
死んで詫びろ！
Go die!
Moron!
金返せ！
クズ！
Pay us back!
Dickwad!
振ってない…
はっ？
No roll.
えっ？何だって？
Huh?
ふ… 振ってない
No roll.
よく考えると わしは
I've been thinking, and I realized. I didn't really roll with the 4-5-6 dice.
シゴロ賽を振ってない…
振ってない
I didn't.
I didn't roll the 4-5-6 dice.
わしはシゴロ賽を振ってない
Kaiji grabbed the bowl before the dice settled.
カイジ君がどんぶりを取った
あの時
サイコロは まだ回っていた
The roll wasn't complete yet.
目はまだ出ていなかった
つまり この勝負は未確定！
So we're not done yet!
We're not finished!
成立してない！
So I haven't technically cheated!
だからイカサマもクソもない
That doesn't count!
不成立！ノーカウント！
ノーカウント！
It doesn't count! It doesn't count!
ノーカウントなんだ！
ノーカン！ノーカン！
ノーカン！ノーカン！ノーカン…
Doesn't count doesn't count doesn't count!
はい！ノーカン…
何だと！こら！
It doesn't count!
ふざけんな！
適当なこと言うな！
Fuck that!
Like hell!
イカサマ野郎！
ノーカウント…
Cheater!
It doesn't count!
目が出てなきゃノーカウントだ
It doesn't count until the dice come up!
マジで言うか？
この野郎 ぶっ殺…
What!?
Let's ki—
Wait.
よせ
Kaiji...
カイジさん
He may be reaching, but he's getting somewhere.
苦し紛れの言い訳にしちゃ
痛いところ突いてるぜ
He has a point.
まんざら理がないわけでもない
何言ってんだよ！カイジさん！
What, Kaiji!?
いや さすがにカイジ君は聡明だ
I knew you were clever, Kaiji!
目が出てなけりゃ
サイコロは未使用
Until the dice stop, a roll isn't over!
Right? It doesn't count!
な？ノーカウントだ
We can do it over!
勝負は やり直し
普通のサイコロで改めてやり直し
Try again with normal—
冗談じゃねえ
えっ？
Cut the shit.
A do-over? I'll pass.
やり直しなんてのは
ごめんこうむる
But...
だが
だ… だが？
But?
I could keep going, maybe.
続行っていうなら考えてもいいぜ
Keep going?
続行？
そうさ
Yeah. You and your buddies have been winning sharing those dice.
お前らは ここまで仲間うちだけで
こんな特殊な賽を回して
勝ち続けてきた
いや… だからそれは
Well, you know...
フッ あえて そのルールで
続行といこうじゃないか
I'll play by those rules.
えっ？
ただし
But you get the lowest roll these 4-5-6 dice can make.
あんたの目は
このシゴロ賽における最低の目
A 4.
４だ
４？
Four?
Did you expect even less of a penalty?
このくらいのペナルティは
当然だろ
うっ…
そして その４の目に対して
And all six of us are going to roll with loaded dice against that.
俺たち６人 同じく
特殊なサイを使って勝負する
How about it?
それでどうだ？
班長…
Boss...
バカめ　やった！やったやった！
ノーカウントが生きた！
Idiot!
I did it! He let it pass!
I though if I got caught I'd have to pay double, triple,
こんなイカサマがバレたら
普通は張った額の２倍か３倍
いや　過去にさかのぼっての
弁済も考えられた
no, pay everything back! But instead we continue?
それを続行！
Even if all six roll a 4-5-6, at double 507,000 the most I'll pay is just over a million!
仮に奴ら６人全員が
シゴロを出しても
50万7000の倍
100万ちょいの負けで決着がつく
All I need to do is make it through this, and then act contrite!
ここを切り抜ければ あとは
うやむやにしちまえばいい
I'm still alive!
生き残った 生き残った
生き残った！
I'm still alive!!!
お人よしめ
What a pushover.
勝負が無効になって
全部 無駄になることを恐れおって
I thought I'd lose everything!
フフフ… やっぱバカじゃん
ハハハ…
He must be retarded!
押し返した
ゴネ得 ゴネ得 ゴネ得！
I turned it around, just by complaining!
So how about it? We gonna do this or no?
おい どうなんだ？
受けるのか？受けないのか？
く… 苦しい条件だが
You're killing me, but...
仕方あるまい
おお！
I can't refuse.
よし
All right.
カイジはまず この１番手
沼川に振らせる
First, Kaiji has Numakawa, the first player, roll.
His roll is a 4! A draw with Ohtsuki!
出目は４　大槻と引き分ける
And then!
そして…
もう一度 確認する
Let's make this perfectly clear.
As a dealer, you rolled a 4. Now all of us are rolling against that.
親の１回目　あんたの目は４
それを受けて俺たちが振る
None of us are using normal dice.
その賽は通常の賽じゃない
前もって用意した特殊な賽だ
We're using specially-prepared dice.
Just like your side, we're sharing our dice between us.
その特殊賽を
あんたらがそうしたように
俺たちも仲間うちで回して使う
No problems, right?
構わないんだな？それで
うう…
ウザいな もう
Dude, whatever, just roll.
いいからさっさと
振れっちゅうんじゃい
Fine. I'm getting sick of this.
わ… 分かった
いい加減 演技も疲れるわ
Then let's get this started.
それじゃ始めるか
うん？
三好
Miyoshi.
ちょっと割に合わないって
思ったろ
This ain't good enough, is it?
あっ…
ここで６人が勝負したとして
If we all take him on with these,
we walk out of here with maybe an extra five hundred thou.
入ってくるのはプラス50万
If we're really lucky, eight hundred or a million.
いや　80万か100万
Could be one, could be the other,
それは分からないが
but it's not enough of a reward for blowing the doors off his trick.
あれだけのイカサマを
暴いた割には その程度かって
ま… まあ確かに
Yeah, I guess...
フッ　安心しろ
Don't worry.
済ますわけねえだろ
そんなもんで！
He'll have to pay...
A lot more!
念力が賽の目を
左右するんだったな？
Karma is guiding these dice!
Suck on this!
食らえ！
This is karmic punishment!
因果応報　天誅
This is what you get for cheating!
これがお前のイカサマの報いだ！
What!?
He rolls snake eyes! They pay five times!
目はピンゾロ　５倍づけ
What are these dice!?
な… 何じゃ このサイコロ！
１！１！１！
One, one, one!
Nothing but ones on each side! One one one one!
６面全部ピンじゃねえか！
ピン ピン ピン！
These are our dice.
こっちはこっちで
用意させてもらった
バカもん！通るか こんなもん！
Bullshit! I'm not gonna—
念押ししたはずだ
お前たちと同じように
Don't you remember? We agreed that we'd each use our own special dice.
前もって用意した
特殊賽を使うと
だから それは同じサイコロを…
I thought they were the same—
シゴロ賽を使うとは
一言も言ってない
I never said we were using the 4-5-6 dice!
えっ？
特殊賽を仲間うちで回す
Just that each of us would share our own!
Share!?
No! This is bullshit!
ダメ！通るか そんなメチャクチャ
無法だ！
Not happening!
いいや
えっ？
Oh yes it is.
Kaiji's right.
カイジ君の言うとおりだ
お前は認めとったぞ
You agreed to it.
特殊賽を使うことも
仲間うちで回すことも
About the special dice, and about the sharing.
そうだそうだ！
観念しろ！
Yeah!
大体 てめえは散々
汚ねえことやっておいて
You're the one who was playing dirty to begin with, why do you care about the rules now!?
今さら何が無法だ！
恥を知れ！
Learn some shame!
Sit back down!
座れよ
座れ！
Sit down! Sit down!
座れ！座れ！座れ！…
Kaiji had waited for this mood!
カイジが欲しかったのは この空気
It is why he egged Ohtsuki on!
周りが一丸となって
大槻を責め立てる
Establish the narrative, and turn the audience to his side!
理を通し心情的に
周りを味方につける
Without it, he could never corner Ohtsuki!
そうでなければ
大槻を追い詰めることはできない
いけ　遠慮なく
Go right ahead.
Okay!
はい
ピンゾロ　ピンゾロ
Snake eyes.
Snake eyes!
Snake eyes!!!
ピンゾロ
Snake! Eyes!
ピンゾロ！ピンゾロ！
SNAKE EYES!!!
Six snake eyes in a row!
６連続ピンゾロ
カイジたち４５組の張り
50万7000が
Kaiji and the others had bet 507,000 perica,
その５倍 253万5000に
膨れ上がる！
but this becomes 2,535,000!
You're gonna have to go fetch your safe to pay up.
こいつを払うには
持ってくるしかねえな
金庫
き…
The box you've been keeping the perica you were saving up in!
お前がゴッソリ貯め込んだ
ペリカの詰まった千両箱
Go get it.
そいつを持ってきてもらおうか
He really was stashing it away?
ほんとだったんだな
貯め込んでるって噂
どんぐらいあんだ？
1000万　いや2000万か？
Wonder how much he's got.
Ten million? Twenty million?
あの野郎 汚ねえ奴だ
What a scumbag!
目標の2000万
あとちょっとだったのに
I almost made it to twenty million...
253万5000だな
There it is. 2,535,000 perica.
おお！
すげえ！
Oh wow!
やった！
All right!
すげえ… すげえぞ！
Holy crap!
待てよ
ああ？
Hold it.
Where are you going?
どこに行く？
どこって
What do you mean, where?
今夜はもう休ませてもらう
I've had enough for tonight. Isawa and Numakawa can run things.
あとの仕切りは石和と沼川がやる
Keep going if you want to.
皆の衆で勝手にやってくれ
ほう　やめるんだ？
一度負けたくらいで
Quitting already?
You only lost once.
えっ？カ… カイジ君
Come on, Kaiji, isn't that enough?
もうこれ以上 いじめんでくれよ
まあ 気持ちは
分からないこともない
Well, I can't say I don't understand where you're coming from.
でも親は
やり切ってもらわないとな
But you need to finish your turn as dealer.
はっ…
忘れたのか？
Don't you remember?
Dealers go twice. You're only off the hook if you roll a 1, something worse, or a pisser.
親は２回　１回で終われるのは
１の目以下かションベンの時だけ
And your first roll was a 4.
あんたの１回目は
４だったじゃないか
Sit the fuck down.
座れよ　もう一度
あんたの親で続行だ
You're dealing again.
We keep going.
Again!?
もう一度？
張らせてもらう　もう一度
We're betting against you.
One more time.
All in.
全額
Together, their bets came to 3,042,000 perica!
積み上げられたのは
総額304万2000
And of course, the rules haven't changed.
無論 ルールはさっきと同じ
特殊サイを使う
Special dice are in play.
Go right ahead with yours.
遠慮なく使ってくれ
なっ…
We'll be using ours.
俺たちも使わせてもらうんだから
似たようなものを
Fair's fair, right?
304万2000
この金が５倍づけとなれば
3,042,000!
If he pays five times, over 15 million!
1500万以上
そ… そ… そんな
What!?
What's going on!?
どういうことよ これ！
さっきの再現だ
It's happening again!
班長の支出はざっと1800万だ！
The foreman's gonna be paying out 18 million tonight!
すげえ！
ブッ飛ぶぞ 奴の金庫の金全部！
Holy shit!
That's every penny he has!
Kaiji has cornered Ohtsuki!
カイジ　ついに大槻を追い詰めた
At the edge of the abyss!
地獄の淵へと
Normally in chinchiro, once you roll, everyone's focused on the bowl.
But during your first roll... You were looking straight into my eyes.
Trying to see if I knew you were cheating.
If you hadn't been looking at me like that, I'd have made a grab.